"We don't want to give anyone sleepless nights."
Ghostwatch is a horror, mystery, tv movie film directed by Lesley Manning.
For Halloween 1992, the BBC decides to broadcast an investigation into the
supernatural, hosted by TV chat-show legend Michael Parkinson.
Parky (assisted by Mike Smith, Sarah Greene & Craig Charles) and a camera crew
attempt to discover the truth behind the most haunted house in Britain.
This ground-breaking live television experiment does not go as planned, however.
Presenter, played by Michael Parkinson.
Reporter, played by Sarah Greene.
Interviewer, played by Craig Charles.
Phone-In Presenter, played by Mike Smith.
Dr. Lin Pascoe, played by Gillian Bevan.
Pamela Early, played by Brid Brennan.
Ghostwatch is a British supernatural horror pseudo-documentary television
film, first broadcast on BBC1 on Halloween night, 1992.
Written by Stephen Volk, and directed by Lesley Manning, the drama was produced for the BBC
anthology series Screen One by Richard Broke, Ruth Baumgarten and Derek Nelson.
Despite having been recorded weeks in advance, the
narrative was presented as live television.
During and following its first and only UK television broadcast, the show attracted a considerable furor, resulting in an estimated 1,000,000  phone call
enquiries to the BBC switchboard on the night of broadcast, comprising a mixture of complaints and praise for the programme's unique presentation.
This outrage is often compared to Orson Welles' 1938 The War of the Worlds radio broadcast and the 1994 Without
Warning television film, both of which also allegedly caused nationwide panic in the United States.
Ghostwatch has never been repeated on UK television.
It has been repeated internationally, on stations such as the Canadian digital
channel Scream for Halloween 2004, and the Belgian channel Canvas in 2008.
It became available on the American streaming video service Shudder in 2017,
and it was made available on the Internet Archive the same year.
There have been three UK home video releases.
In 2002, the British Film Institute released a 10th Anniversary edition on VHS and DVD, and 101
Films issued a DVD release in 2011 and a 30th Anniversary Blu-ray release in 2022.
In 2016, the BBC Store made the film available as part of the
Frightmares collection, marking Halloween.
A retrospective documentary, Ghostwatch: Behind the Curtains, based on the film's lasting impact, was released on DVD in 2013
(having been in production between 2007 and 2012), featuring interviews with many of the original cast and crew.
It too was made available as part of the BBC Store Frightmares
collection, and shortly after release, the BFI Mediatheque.
The film explores themes of talk show, halloween,
paranormal, ghost, found footage.
The tone is dark and mind_bending.